<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-29T04:43:40-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dani.is</title><subtitle>Portfolio | Dani is a UX Designer</subtitle><author><name>Dani J</name></author><entry><title type="html">Design System Development</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/Design-System-Development.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design System Development" /><published>2024-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/Design-System-Development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/Design-System-Development.html"><![CDATA[<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
<h2>Overview</h2>

<p>The company had three different channels for conducting business. Retail, Consumer-direct, and wholesale. B2C,
    retail, and consumer-direct part of the company had multiple subsidiaries that required different branding.
    Similarly, wholesale customers wanted to apply their own branding to our provided services as well.</p>

<p>Another issue with their proprietary system was front-end development speed. There were no guidelines nor component library for repetitive items, even for a button. Every button on different pages was slightly different.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <video class="img-fluid" muted="" autoplay="" loop="" controls="">
                <source src="/img/posts/design-system-development/color-token.webm" type="video/webm">
            </video>
            <span class="caption text-muted">Color Tokens</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/design-system-development/typography-token.png">
<span class="caption text-muted">Typography Tokens</span>
        </div>
    </div>

</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
<h2>Primitive Tokens</h2>
<p>Based on our products’ needs and goals, I set up various tokens. As we were not using semantic tokens at the moment, the color palettes itself are following WCAG 2.0 (and 3.0 for orange tone) to deal with any kind of scenarios.</p>

<p>Typography token is using 3 different primitive tokens, font size, font weight, and line height. By doing this, each theme can be easily controlled for its purpose.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/design-system-development/namingConvention-tokens.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Token Naming Convention</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/design-system-development/semantic-token.png">
<span class="caption text-muted">Semantic Token Hierarchy</span>
        </div>
    </div>

</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
<h2>Component & Semantic Tokens</h2>

<p>Figma didn’t have a native way to apply tokens properly but with limited library features. I was able to make a decent way to apply different themes with library swap feature, but it was still, too much to ask new designers who are not familiar with Figma.</p>
<p>Thankfully, Figma introduced variable feature. And I was able to update all the components with it quickly.</p>
<p>While making and applying component tokens, I realized two things; In code, token naming convention is not consistent It’s a good time to apply Semantic Tokens.</p>
<p>I grabbed front-end engineers and showed possible two naming conventions, and suggestions for applying semantic tokens for actions. Thanks to the great front-end engineering team, we connected Figma tokens to the code. Figma token update means code is updated automatically.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/design-system-development/guidelines.png">
</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
<h2 class="section-heading">Product for Our Team</h2>

<p>I believe making a design system is making a product for designers and software engineers. So I did everything I could to make it convenient for them. Slot and table component is some of the my efforts to make that possible.</p>

<p>With Slot component, designers could update the contents inside of a component without disconnecting its library. (slot component concept is originally from Atlassian. See Atlassian Figma File)</p>

<p>Working on a financial product meant a lot of tables. (or a similar structure) Designers always needed to spend lots of time moving around table borders, cells, rows, and columns. After the update, designers never needed to work more than 5 minutes on any kind of updates for tables.</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Dani J</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Overview]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mortgage Application Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/06/Mortgage-Application-Design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mortgage Application Design" /><published>2023-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/06/Mortgage-Application-Design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/06/Mortgage-Application-Design.html"><![CDATA[<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2>Overview</h2>

    <p>Based on research on the existing product, its customers, other products from competitors, and mortgage rules and
        regulations, I suggested two different approaches. Updating visuals with minimal changes and overhauling the
        application. The stakeholders wanted to go with a fast way, updating visuals.</p>

    <p>Even though it was a visual update, I believed there would be some room and opportunities to make general UX
        better. I threw a presentation about some opportunities that can improve the product while updating visuals.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2>Information Hierarchy</h2>
    <p>Even though the originating system that was connected to the product had certain items in the same group, the
        product didn’t need to follow the same grouping rule. There was a consumer report including a review of this
        product which states navigating issues.</p>

    <p>I broke down the Uniform Residential Loan Application, URLA, into several parts along with other competitors and
        ours. The flow chart was shared with any new project contributors for an easy and quick overview.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/mortgage-application-development/information-hierarchy-3.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Boring, long, mandatory questionaries in the old product</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <video class="img-fluid" muted="" autoplay="" loop="" controls="">
                <source src="/img/posts/mortgage-application-development/information-hierarchy-4.webm"
                    type="video/webm">
            </video>
            <span class="caption text-muted">Distributed in multiple "related" pages</span>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/mortgage-application-development/information-hierarchy-1.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Data entry forms can be easier for users. I grouped in multiple different ways to find the best way</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <video class="img-fluid" muted="" autoplay="" loop="" controls="">
                <source src="/img/posts/mortgage-application-development/information-hierarchy-2.webm"
                    type="video/webm">
            </video>
            <span class="caption text-muted">After several conversations with stakeholders, long list of dropdown menu became this</span>
        </div>
    </div>

</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2>Funnel type of data entry</h2>
    <p>I have been exposed enough to understand several regulations regarding the mortgage application and some marketing techniques. Combining these two into one, I suggested gathering estimated information is better than capturing the precise information upfront.</p>

    <p>TRID rule requires lenders to provide loan estimates and closing disclosures to the borrower within 3 business days. The timer starts clocking once the borrower provides certain information. However, lenders easily guess some values of that information.</p>

    <p>
        Instead of doing that, I suggested separate data entry into two parts, assigning easy and attracting ones up-front and complicated and time consuming ones later, in another existing product, borrower portal.
    </p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/mortgage-application-development/industry-research-1.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Capture from presentation files. A brief explanation of TRID</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/mortgage-application-development/industry-research-2.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Comparing competitors and the organization's products in TRID Rule Perspective</span>
        </div>
    </div>

</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2>Competitor Research</h2>
    <p>I have been exposed enough to understand several regulations regarding the mortgage application and some marketing techniques. Combining these two into one, I suggested gathering estimated information is better than capturing the precise information upfront.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/mortgage-application-development/competitor-research-1.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">UI and UX Comparison of Competitors</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/mortgage-application-development/competitor-research-2.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Flow Charts of Competitors</span>
        </div>
    </div>

</div>]]></content><author><name>Dani J</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Overview]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">at Cardinal Financial</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/06/at-Cardinal-Financial.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="at Cardinal Financial" /><published>2022-09-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/09/06/at-Cardinal-Financial</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/06/at-Cardinal-Financial.html"><![CDATA[<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2>Overview</h2>

    <p>I also led the development of a comprehensive design system that emphasized theming and a precise connection between design and code, which was utilized across five different products.</p>

    <p>My efforts in fostering a supportive environment not only significantly reduced unnecessary tasks and Figma-related inquiries but also led to the expansion of the team with three additional UX designers.</p>

    <p>
        Additionally, I served as an internal UX consultant for various features in proprietary loan origination system. Providing essential research, guidance, prototypes, and conceptual designs, contributed in the company's approach to user experience design.
    </p>
</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2>Designer Workshop</h2>
    <p>I started bi-weekly designer only meetings to share thoughts and knowledges, created a Zoom channel to make new designers feel comfortable and confident about what they are doing and to align our UX experience voice as a team.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-cardinal/tutorials-1.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Figma quick guide for FE Engineers</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-cardinal/tutorials-2.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Advanced prototyping tutorial for Designers</span>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2>Figma Admin and Guide</h2>
    <p>Established Figma file organizing rule. Using Asana widget on the cover of a file, viewers can check the feature's progress and connect it to its related links. A better naming convention in the library helped designers with faster and more accurate search. Provided multiple guides for designers and engineers.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row align-items-end">
        <div class="col-md-4">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-cardinal/designer-meeting-4.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Slot in Figma tutorial</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-4">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-cardinal/designer-meeting-2.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Checkbox prototype tutorial</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-4">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-cardinal/designer-meeting-3.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Timer prototype tutorial</span>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>

<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2>Other UX Related Support</h2>
    <p>Numerous proprietary loan origination system UX consultations with concept designs, accessible color palette for multiple products, UX research on our & competitor products.</p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-cardinal/misc-1.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Data Visualization Colors, priortizing accessibility</span>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-cardinal/misc-2.png">
            <span class="caption text-muted">Competitor UX Research and Report</span>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Dani J</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Overview]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">at RMK</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/06/at-RMK-Financial.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="at RMK" /><published>2022-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/06/at-RMK-Financial</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/06/at-RMK-Financial.html"><![CDATA[<div class="col-md-8 mx-auto py-5">
    <h2 id="Overview" class="accent toc">Overview</h2>
    <p>
    </p>
    <li>
        Design Components and UI/UX Design for Proprietary web LOS</li>
    <li>
        UI/UX Design for Public Websites and Landing Pages</li>
    <li>
        automation with RPA</li>
    <p></p>
    <p>
        The company was highly focused on the wholesale mortgage industry. I interacted with internal
        account executives and signed up brokers to enhance their overall experiences with the website and
        the company's services.
    </p>
    <p>
        As a sole UI/UX designer, I actively looked for issues in the proprietary LOS and suggested multiple
        solutions to the stakeholders directly, including CEO.
    </p>
    <p>
        CFPB regulations were always considered while creating designs for public and marketing materials
        which made faster communication and easy approval possible with the internal compliance team.
    </p>
    <p>
        After understanding more about the mortgage industry and our customers' needs, I was able to
        participate in the development of mortgage programs such as Non-QM DSCR.
    </p>
</div>

<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-6 text-center">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-RMK/mobile-app.png">
            <p class="mt-2">Mobile App for Mortgage Brokers</p>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6 text-center">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-RMK/websites-3.png">
            <p class="mt-2">LOS Interface Update with Design System</p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-12 text-center">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-RMK/websites-2.png">
            <p class="mt-2">Multiple Feature Developments for Work Portal</p>
        </div>

    </div>
</div>
<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-12 text-center">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-RMK/websites-1.png">
            <p class="mt-2">Designed and Coded Multiple Public Websites and Contents</p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-12 text-center">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-RMK/misc-2.png">
            <p class="mt-2">Designed Marketing Materials</p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-12 text-center">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-RMK/misc-3.png">
            <p class="mt-2">Created Employee Guides for New Features</p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<div class="col-12 py-5">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-12 text-center">
            <img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/at-RMK/misc-1.png">
            <p class="mt-2">Designed Brand Materials</p>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Dani J</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Overview Design Components and UI/UX Design for Proprietary web LOS UI/UX Design for Public Websites and Landing Pages automation with RPA The company was highly focused on the wholesale mortgage industry. I interacted with internal account executives and signed up brokers to enhance their overall experiences with the website and the company's services. As a sole UI/UX designer, I actively looked for issues in the proprietary LOS and suggested multiple solutions to the stakeholders directly, including CEO. CFPB regulations were always considered while creating designs for public and marketing materials which made faster communication and easy approval possible with the internal compliance team. After understanding more about the mortgage industry and our customers' needs, I was able to participate in the development of mortgage programs such as Non-QM DSCR.]]></summary></entry></feed>